Pavlos Karalis

I'm a Full-Stack Developer capable of tackling a project from multiple-perspectives, and can dependably deliver tailored, maintainable results via a crafted approach. Furthermore, with 8 years of prior experience as a DC metro area event photographer, resourcefulness, professionalism, and ingenuity have all become second nature.

Rockville, Maryland
(301) 642-5129
pavloskaralis@gmail.com
Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

DEVELOPER EXPERIENCE | DEVELOPER PORTFOLIO

Software Engineering Fellow — *General Assembly*

2019 - 2020

700 Hour course on Full-Stack Development, Frameworks, and APIs.

Traveler: Full-Stack trip planner with shared user model Project

React, Redux-Thunk, Rails, PostgreSQL, Bcrypt README.md

Spell ✓ It: Full-Stack spell checker with interactive text Project

Angular, Spring Boot, MySQL, Regex, SCSS README.md

Appstractor: Full-stack image filter application/gallery Project

Express, Mongoose, EJS, jQuery, Unsplash API README.md

Go-Fish: 2 to 4 player DOM game against programmed AI Project
jQuery, Vanilla JavaScript, Photoshop README.md

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Real Estate Photographer — *Redfin*

2018 - PRESENT

- Capturing residential properties for Redfin's Maryland region.
- Onboarding and mentoring new photographer employees.

Freelance Photographer — Pavlos Karalis Photography

2012 - 2019

- Captured headshots, events, and weddings for various clientele.
- Hired and managed assistant photographers and videographers.

Event Photographer — *EPNAC*

2015 - 2018

- Captured corporate/government events with prominent speakers.
- Oversaw team travel assignments in cities across the country.

EDUCATION

Corcoran College of Art and Design — BFA Photography

Frontend

React

Redux-Thunk

Angular TypeScript HTML5 CSS3

Javascript ES6

Axios SCSS jQuery Bootstrap

Backend

Node.js Express

Ruby Rails Java

SpringBoot MongoDB

PostgreSQL MySQL

Passport.js Bcrypt

EJS JSX MVC

Restful Routes

Other

Github Postman

Adobe Creative Suite